Finding Aid for the Delmore Schwartz Papers LSC.1005
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Books from the library of Delmore Schwartz
  - Idea of an American novel. New York: Crowell, 1961, Call number: PS371.R82i (Box 16)
  - Mysticism and logic. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1957, Call number: B1649.R961 M9 1957 (Box 57)
  - If she should die: a mystery. New York: Popular Library, 1964, Call number: PS3568.Y3985 I3 1964 (Box 57)
  - New approach to Joyce: the portrait of the artist as a guidebook. Berkeley: University of California Press, 1962, Call number: PR6019.O9 P648 1962 (Box 49)
  - Selected essays translated and edited by Francis Steegmuller and Norbert Guterman. Garden City, N.Y.: Anchor Books, 1964, Call number: PQ2391.Z2 S7 1964 (Box 56)
  - Seamarks translation by Wallace Fowlie. New York: Harper, 1961, Call number: PQ2623.L524 A46 1961 (Box 68)
  - Age of magnificence: the Memoirs of the Duc de Saint-Simon Selected, edited and translated by Sanche de Gramont [Ted Morgan]. New York: Capricorn Books, 1964, Call number: DC130.S2 A181 1964 (Box 21)
  - Lilith. New York: Bantam, 1962, Call number: PS3569.A458 L5 1962 (Box 48)
  - Raise high the roof beam, carpenters; and, Seymour: an introduction. Toronto; New York: Bantam Books, 1965, Call number: PS3537.A426 R3 1965 (Box 56)
  - Three philosophical poets: Lucretius, Dante, Goethe. New York: Doubleday, 1938, Call number: PN1077.S3 1938 (Box 21)
  - Persons and places. New York: Scribner, 1944, Call number: B945.S24 A3 1945 v.2 (Box 58)
  - Language: an introduction to the study of speech. New York: Harcourt, Brace & Co., 1949, Call number: P105.S2 1949 (Box 48)
  - Handwriting analysis. New York: Pyramid Books, 1956, Call number: BF891.S257 (Box 8)
  - Basic teachings of the great psychologists in collaboration with Kenneth R. Stafford. Garden City, N.Y.: Dolphin Books, 1965, Call number: BF131.S226 1965 (Box 56)
  - Age of reason translated from the French by Eric Sutton. New York: Bantam Books, 1964, Call number: PQ2637.A82 A71 1964 (Box 48)
  - Existentialism translated by Bernard Frechtman. New York: Philosophical Library, 1947, Call number: BD355.S324 1947 (Box 58)
  - 50 qasidah min al-shir al-Amiriki al-muasir ikhtaraha wa-tarjamaha wa-qaddama la-ha Tawfiq Sayigh. Bayrut: Dar al-Yaqazah al-Arabiyah, 1963, Call number: PS619.A7 K45 1963 (Box 57)
  - Man's place in nature Translated, and with an introduction by Hans Meyerhoff. New York: Noonday Press, 1962, Call number: BD431.S32sE 1962 (Box 21)
  - Private dooms and public destinations: poems, 1945-1962. Denver: A. Swallow, 1962, Call number: PS3537.C45 P7 (Box 22)
  - Good & bad weather. Toronto; New York: Bantam Books, 1966, Call number: PS3569.C485 G66 1966 (Box 6)
  - Scandal's child. New York: Pocket Books, 1964, Call number: PS3537.C345 S23 1964 (Box 55)
  - Story, a critical anthology. New York: Prentice-Hall, 1950, Call number: PN6014.S39s; Title page missing. (Box 24)
  - Genesis... [New York: J. Laughlin, 1943, Call number: PS3537.S39g v.1 (Box 10)
    Presentation copy from the author to Maurice Zolotow.
  - In dreams begin responsibilities. Norfolk, Conn.: New Directions, 1938, Call number: PS3537.C79 I5 1938 (Box 46)
  - Shenandoah. Norfolk, Conn.: New directions, 1941, Call number: PS3537.C79 S5 1941 (Box 46)
  - Scrimshaw [poems] New York: Macmillan, 1959, Call number: PS3537.S425sc (Box 68)
  - History of the world in two hundred & forty pages Translated from the French by Gerard Hopkins. [New York]: New American Library, 1953, Call number: D21.S394 1953 (Box 16)
  - Women in antiquity. New York: Collier Books, 1962, Call number: HQ1127.S4 1962 (Box 57)
  - Abstract painting: 50 years of accomplishment, from Kandinsky to the present Text by Michel Seuphor [pseud. Translated from the French by Haakon Chevalier]. New York: Dell, 1964, Call number: ND195.B45 (Box 16)
  - Survival of the pagan gods: the mythological tradition and its place in Renaissance humanism and art by Jean Seznec; translated from the French by Barbara F. Sessions. New York: Harper, 1961, Call number: BR135.S522sE 1961 (Box 68)
  - New variorum edition of Shakespeare edited by Horace Howard Furness. New York: Dover Publications, 1963, Call number: PR2753.F98 1963 (Box 66, 22)
    Vol.1 in box 66, vol.6,8 in box 22.
  - Sonnets introduction by W.H. Auden; edited by William Burto. New York: New American Library; London: New English Library, 1964, Call number: PR2848.A2 B837 (Box 16)
  - Measure for measure edited by R.C. Bald. Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1956, Call number: PR2824.A2 B3 1956 (Box 20)
  - Tragedy of King Lear edited by Alfred Harbage. Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1958, Call number: PR2819.A2 H25 1958 (Box 20)
  - Antony and Cleopatra general editor Louis B. Wright, assistant editor Virginia A. LaMar. New York: Washington Square Press, 1961, Call number: PR2802.A2 W7 (Box 21)
  - Four great comedies: A midsummer night's dream. As you like it. Twelfth night. The tempest Cambridge text and glossaries, complete and unabridged; Edited by William Aldis Wright; introductions by Mark Van Doren, synopses by J. Walker McSpadden, illus New York: Washington Square Press, 1960, Call number: PR2753.C8 1948 (Box 21)
  - Hamlet edited by R.C. Bald. New York: F.S. Crofts & co., 1946, Call number: PR2807.A2 B2 1946 (Box 21)
  - Tragedy of Julius Caesar edited by Louis B. Wright, Virginia A. LaMar. New York: Washington Square Press, 1960, Call number: PR2808.A2 W75 (Box 21)
  - Macbeth edited by Kenneth Muir. New York: Random House, 1964, Call number: PR2823.A2 M78 1964 (Box 22)
  - Othello: the Moor of Venice edited by Mark Eccles. New York: Appleton-Century-Crofts, 1946, Call number: PR2829.A2 E2 1946 (Box 40)
  - Taming of the shrew edited by Richard Hosley. Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1964, Call number: PR2832.A2 H6 1964 (Box 40)
  - Tempest: a comedy newly edited from the First Folio text. New York: F.S. Crofts & Co., 1946, Call number: PR2833.A2 T46 1946 (Box 57)
  - Tragedy of Coriolanus edited by Louis Booker Wright. New York: Washington Square Press, 1962, Call number: PR2805.A2 W7x (Box 67)
  - Case pending. New York: Dell, 1964, Call number: PS3562.I54 C3 1964 (Box 56)
  - Chaucer and the Roman poets. Cambridge: Harvard university press, 1929, Call number: PR1912.A3 S5 1929 (Box 52)
  - Green tree in Gedde. New York: New American Library, 1966, Call number: PR6069.S531g 1966 (Box 5)
  - Chronicles of the Crusades. Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1963, Call number: D151.S535c (Box 7)
  - Fasting can save your life. Chicago, Ill.: Natural Hygiene Press, 1964, Call number: RM226.5.S46 1964 (Box 56)
  - Man downstairs. New York, N.Y.: New American Library, 1964, Call number: PS3569.H554 M36 1964 (Box 53)
  - Rapt in glory. New York: Pocket Books: Distributed by Affiliated Pub., 1964, Call number: PS3569.I415 R37 1964 (Box 55)
  - Key to the door. New York: New American Library, 1963, Call number: PR6037.I55 K49 1963 (Box 48)
  - Inspector Maigret in New York's underworld: Maigret a New York translated from the French by Adrienne Foulke. [New York]: New American Library, 1955, Call number: PQ2637.I53 I56 1955 (Box 21)
  - Stain on the snow translated by John Petrie. Baltimore, Md.: Penguin Books, 1964, Call number: PQ2637.I53 S73 (Box 21)
  - Bells of Bicetre translated from the French by Jean Stewart. New York: New American Library, 1965, Call number: PQ2637.S59 A61E 1965 (Box 53)
  - Pushkin edited and introduced by Ernest J. Simmons. New York: Dell, 1961, Call number: PG3350 .S52 1961 (Box 37)
  - Pocket book of great operas illustrated by Louis Glanzman. New York: Pocket Books, 1949, Call number: MT95.S6 1949 (Box 40)
  - Concise etymological dictionary of the English language. New York: Capricorn Books, 1963, Call number: PE1580.S52 1963 (Box 5)
  - Write me a poem, baby drawings by John V. Morris. Boston: Little, Brown, 1956, Call number: PS3537.S65366w (Box 15)
  - Poor H. Allen Smith's almanac: a comic compendium loaded with wisdom & laughter; together with a generous lagniappe of questionable natural history. Greenwich, Conn.: Fawcett publications, 1965, Call number: PS3537.N4655 P6 1965 (Box 40)
  - From fish to philosopher. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1961, Call number: QH369.S58 1961 (Box 40)
  - Our faces, our words. New York: W.W. Norton, 1964, Call number: E185.61.S64o (Box 69)
  - Expedition of Humphry Clinker with a foreword by Monroe Engel. New York: New American Library, 1960, Call number: PR3694.E8 1960 (Box 17)
  - Affair. New York: Scribner, 1960, Call number: PR6037.N58 A33 1960 (Box 53)
  - War: a concise history, 1939-1945 introduction by Eric Sevareid. New York: Dell, 1964, Call number: D743.S58 1964 (Box 56)
  - Magic Christian. New York: Random House, 1960, Call number: PS3537.S7186m (Box 15)
  - Flaubert: a biography. New York: Grove Press, 1952, Call number: PQ2247.S74f 1952 (Box 68)
  - Mysticism in world religion. Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1963, Call number: BL625.S65 (Box 16)
  - Great German short stories edited and introduced by Stephen Spender. [New York: Dell Pub. Co.], 1960, Call number: PT1327.S6 1960 (Box 40)
  - Letters from an American farmer. New York: E.P. Dutton, 1957, Call number: E163.C825 1957 (Box 16)
  - Elephant walk. New York: Ballantine, 1948, Call number: PR6013.E668 E44 1948 (Box 53)
  - Florentine ring. New York: Paperback Library, 1964, Call number: PS3569.T333 F56 1964 (Box 55)
  - Score. New York: Pocket Books, 1964, Call number: PS3573.E9 S36 1964 (Box 54)
  - Wall of noise: a novel. New York: Bantam, 1963, Call number: PS3537.T3198 W35 1963 (Box 54)
  - Selected writings of Gertrude Stein edited, with an introduction and notes, by Carl Van Vechten and with an essay on Gertrude Stein by F. W. Dupee. New York: Modern Library, 1962, Call number: PS3537.S819 A14 1962 (Box 15)
  - Charterhouse of Parma translated from the French by C.K. Scott-Moncrieff; with an afterword by Jacques Barzun. [New York]: New American Library, 1962, Call number: PQ2435.C4 S2 1962 (Box 21)
  - Five short novels of Stendhal Translated from the French by C.K. Scott Moncrieff. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday & Co., 1958, Call number: PQ2435.A3 M66 1958 (Box 21)
  - Scarlet and black translated and with an introduction by Margaret R.B. Shaw. London; Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1953, Call number: PQ2435.R713 1953 (Box 21)
  - Lucien Leuwen ("Green huntsman") translated by Louise Varese. [New York]: New Directions, 1950, Call number: PQ2435.V4 1950 (Box 53)
  - Lucien Leuwen ("The telegraph") translated by Louise Varese. New York: New Directions, 1961, Call number: PQ2435.L8 E5 1961 v.2 (Box 68)
  - Life and opinions of Tristram Shandy, gentleman with an afterword by Gerald Weales. New York: New American Library, 1962, Call number: PR3714.T7 1962 (Box 41)
  - Sentimental journey & Journal to Eliza with an afterword by Monroe Engel. New York: New American Library, 1964, Call number: PR3714.S4 F64 1964 (Box 55)
  - Poems selected, and with an introduction by Samuel French Morse. New York: Vintage Books, 1959, Call number: PS3537.T4753 A17 1959 (Box 8)
    Copy 1 in box 8, copy 2 in box 16.
  - Summer houses. New York, N.Y.: Macfadden-Bartell, 1964, Call number: PS3569.T4557 S86 1964 (Box 55)
  - W. B. Yeats: his poetry and thought. Cambridge [Eng.]: University Press, 1964, Call number: PR5907.S84 1964 (Box 53)
  - Medieval English verse translated, with an introduction, by Brian Stone. Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1964, Call number: PR1203.S84 (Box 8)
  - Russian stories = Russkazy (romanized form): stories in the original Russian with translations, critical introductions, notes and vocabulary by the editor. New York: Bantam Books, 1965, Call number: PG3283.S74 1965 (Box 50)
  - Lie down in darkness. New York: New American Library, 1952, Call number: PS3569.T9 L5 1952 (Box 16)
  - Set this house on fire. New York: New American Library, 1961, Call number: PS3569.T9 S47 1960 (Box 54)
  - Twelve Caesars Gaius Suetonius Tranquillus; translated by Robert Graves. [Harmondsworth, Middlesex, Baltimore]: Penguin Books, 1957, Call number: DG277.S7 T5 1957 (Box 16)
  - Penguin encyclopedia. Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1965, Call number: AG5.P376 (Box 5)
  - Art of China, Korea, and Japan. New York: F. A. Praeger, 1963, Call number: N7340.S96 1963 (Box 50)
  - Gulliver's travels with an introduction by Maxwell Geismar. New York: Washington Square Press, 1960, Call number: PR3724.G7 1960 (Box 16)
  - Gulliver's travels: an annotated text with critical essays edited by Robert A. Greenberg. New York: Norton, 1961, Call number: PR3724.G95 1961 (Box 66)
  - Comedy: An essay on comedy [by] George Meredith. Laughter [by] Henri Bergson. introduction and appendix: The meanings of comedy, by Wylie Sypher. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1956, Call number: PN1922.S9 (Box 12)
  - Art history, an anthology of modern criticism. New York: Vintage Books, 1963, Call number: N5303.S994a (Box 16)
  - Four stages of Renaissance style: transformations in art and literature, 1400-1700. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1956, Call number: N6370.S95 (Box 17)
  - Annals of imperial Rome Translated with an introduction by Michael Grant. Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1959, Call number: DG207.T3 G68 1959 (Box 16)
  - Franz Kafka: an interpretation of his works [translated by G. Humphreys Roberts and Roger Senhouse]. New Haven: Yale Univ. Press, 1948, Call number: PT2621.A26z 1948 (Box 59)
  - Life and good times of William Randolph Hearst. New York: Paperback Library, 1962, Call number: PN4874.H4 T4 1962 (Box 54)
  - Reading poems: an introduction to critical study .... New York: Oxford University Press, 1941, Call number: PR1175.T36r; Title page missing. (Box 15)
  - Portrait of the artist as a young dog. New York: New Directions, 1955, Call number: PR6039.H52 Z5 1955 (Box 16)
  - Under milk wood, a play for voices. [New York]: New Directions, 1954, Call number: PR6039.T34u 1954b (Box 16)
  - Collected poems of Dylan Thomas. New York: New Directions, 1957, Call number: PR6039.T34 A17 1957 (Box 24)
  - Adventures in the skin trade, and other stories. [New York: New Directions Pub. Corp.], 1964, Call number: PR6039.T34a 1964b (Box 66)
  - Robert Frost. Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press, 1959, Call number: PS3511.R94 Z95 1959 (Box 49)
  - Dark shadow. New York: Macfadden-Bartell, 1964, Call number: PR6039.H77 S43 1964 (Box 55)
  - History of the Peloponnesian War translated with an introduction by Rex Warner. Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1954, Call number: G505.9.T421h 1954 (Box 20)
  - Reader's guide to James Joyce. New York: Noonday Press, 1959, Call number: PR6019.J85 T4r (Box 21)
  - Reader's guide to Dylan Thomas. New York: Farrar, Straus and Cudahy, 1962, Call number: PR6039.T34 T294 (Box 23)
  - Lame prince: a story. Moscow: Foreign Languages Pub. House, 1958, Call number: PG3476.T6 K5 (Box 58)
  - War and peace translated and with an introduction by Rosemary Edmonds. [Harmondsworth, Middlesex]: Penguin Books, 1957, Call number: PG3366.V6 1957 v.1-2 (Box 8)
  - Anna Karenin translated and with an introduction by Rosemary Edmonds. Melbourne; Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1954, Call number: PG3366.A6 E35 1954 (Box 16)
  - Childhood, boyhood, youth translated and with an introduction by Rosemary Edmonds. Baltimore, Maryland, U.S.A.: Penguin Books, 1964, Call number: PG3366.D413 1964 (Box 16)
  - Short stories of Leo Tolstoy translated by Arthur Mendel and Barbara Makanowitzky. New York: Bantam Books, 1960, Call number: PG3366.A15 1960 (Box 16)
  - Short stories selected and introduced by Ernest J. Simmons. New York: Modern Library, 1964, Call number: PG3366.A13 S56 1964 (Box 24)
  - Short masterpieces by Tolstoy translated by Margaret Wettlin; introduction by F.D. Reeve. New York: Dell, 1963, Call number: PG3366.A13 W43x (Box 27)
  - Fables and fairy tales a new translation by Ann Dunnigan; illustrated by Sheila Greenwald, with a foreword by Raymond Rosenthal. New York: New American Library, 1962, Call number: PG3366.A13 D8 1962 (Box 55)
  - Centuries introduction by John Farrar. New York: Harper, 1960, Call number: BV4831.T7 1960a (Box 9)
  - Shortened history of England. Baltimore, Md.: Penguin Books, 1959, Call number: DA32.T7496 1959 (Box 9)
  - Barchester Towers. New York: Bantam Books., 1959, Call number: PR5684.B2 1959 (Box 37)
  - Warden with an afterword by Geoffrey Tillotson. New York: New American Library, 1964, Call number: PR5684.W25 1964 (Box 55)
  - Fathers and sons translated from the Russian by Constance Garnett; with an introduction by Delmore Schwartz. New York: Harper, 1951, Call number: PG3421.O8 G18 1951 (Box 9)
  - Fathers and sons a new translation by George Reavey; with a foreword by Alan Hodge. [New York]: New American Library, 1961, Call number: PG3421.O8 R4 1961 (Box 16)
  - Hunting sketches a new translation by Bernard Guilbert Guerney, with an afterword by the translator. New York: New American Library, 1962, Call number: PG3421.Z3 1962 (Box 16)
  - Selected tales newly translated with an introduction by David Magarshack. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1960, Call number: PG3421.A2 M44 1960 (Box 16)
  - Adventures of Huckleberry Finn illustrated by Harold Minton. New York: Washington Square Press, 1960, Call number: PZ3.C59 A65 (Box 16)
  - Yeats: a collection of critical essays. Englewood Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, 1963, Call number: PR5907.U59y (Box 31)
  - Reader's guide to William Butler Yeats. New York: Noonday Press, 1959, Call number: PR5907.U5 1959 (Box 39)
  - Same door. Greenwich, Conn.: Fawcett, 1964, Call number: PS3571.P4 S25 1964 (Box 54)
  - Pigeon feathers: and other stories. New York: Crest Book, 1963, Call number: PS3571.P4 P5 1963 (Box 56)
  - Palace of pleasure: an anthology of the novella introduction by Maurice Valency. New York: Capricorn Books, 1960, Call number: PQ4257.B5 V23 (Box 17)
  - Selected writings. [New York: New Directions], 1950, Call number: PQ2643.V23 A14 1950 (Box 24)
  - Art of poetry translated from the French by Denise Folliot; introduction by T. S. Eliot. New York: Vintage Books, 1961, Call number: PN1064.V237 1961 (Box 39)
  - Heine: poet in exile Translated by Harrison Brown. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1956, Call number: PT2328.V32 1956 (Box 24)
  - Happy critic, and other essays. New York: Hill and Wang, 1961, Call number: PS3543.V28ha (Box 24)
  - Kama Sutra of Vatsyayana translated by Sir Richard Burton and F.F. Arbuthnot; edited with a preface by W.G. Archer; introduction by K.M. Panikkar. New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1966, Call number: HQ470.S2 V45E 1966 (Box 8)
  - Complete poetry of Henry Vaughan edited, with an introduction, notes, and variants by French Fogle. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday & Co., 1964, Call number: PR3740.A2 1964 (Box 39)
  - Painting and painters: how to look at a picture, from Giotto to Chagall. Cleveland: World Pub. Co., 1963, Call number: ND1143.V4 (Box 69)
  - Selected poems translated by C. F. MacIntyre. Berkley, Calif.: Univ. of California Press, 1961, Call number: PQ2463.A6 1961 (Box 39)
  - To love and corrupt. New York: Bantam Books, 1964, Call number: PS3572.I32 T6x 1964 (Box 26)
  - Lutte avec l'ange. Paris: Librairie Les Lettres, 1950, Call number: PQ2643.I367 L8 (Box 5)
  - Eclogues and Georgics of Virgil translated by C. Day Lewis. Garden City, N.Y.: Anchor Books, Doubleday & co., 1964, Call number: PA6807.D334b 1964 (Box 39)
  - Aeneid translated into English prose with an introduction by W.F. Jackson Knight. London, England; New York: Penguin, 1958, Call number: PA6807.A5 K55 1958 (Box 56)
  - English poetry and its contribution to the knowledge of a creative principle with a preface by T.S. Eliot. New York: Macmillan, 1950, Call number: PR503.V5 1950 (Box 5)
  - Fault of the apple. New York: Dell, 1963, Call number: PS3545.A4323 F38 1963 (Box 47)
  - Stacy Tower: a novel. Toronto; New York: Bantam, 1964, Call number: PS3545.A619 S72 1964 (Box 47)
  - Jubb. New York: Pocket Books, 1965, Call number: PR6073.A82 J8 1965 (Box 53)
  - Born victim. New York: Avon Books, a division of the Hearst Corporation, 1962, Call number: K636.Z9 W354 1962 (Box 47)
  - Late Mrs. D. New York, N.Y.: Avon Books, a division of the Hearst Corporation, 1962, Call number: PS3573.A97 L2 1962 (Box 47)
  - Tragedy of the Duchess of Malfi. New York: Washington Square Press, 1959, Call number: PR3184.D8 1959 (Box 70)
  - Gods and goddesses in art and legend: great myths as pictured by great masters. New York: Washington Square Press, 1961, Call number: N7760.W45 1961 (Box 70)
  - Romance of words. New York: Dover, 1961, Call number: PE1574.W4 1961 (Box 69)
  - Enemy camp. New York: Pocket Books, 1960, Call number: PS3545.E449 E5 1960 (Box 47)
  - Sound of Bow bells. New York: Fawcett World Library, 1963, Call number: PS3545.E449 S68615 1963 (Box 47)
  - Third angel. New York: Avon Books, a division of the Hearst Corporation, 1954, Call number: PS3545.E449 T485 1954 (Box 47)
  - Fair game: an original novel. New York, N.Y.: Dell, 1964, Call number: PS3573.E3838 F35 1964 (Box 42)
  - Knowledge and wonder: the natural world as man knows it. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1963, Call number: Q162.W4 1963 (Box 38)
  - Dostoevsky; a collection of critical essays. Englewood Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, 1962, Call number: PG3328.W45d (Box 31)
  - Thirteen stories. New York: Harcourt, Brace & World, 1965, Call number: PS3545.E6 1965 (Box 38)
  - Henri Rousseau (1844-1910) text by Alfred Werner. New York: H. Abrams, 1961, Call number: ND553.R67 .W47 1961 (Box 37)
  - Miss Lonelyhearts. New York: Avon, 1959, Call number: PS3545.E8334 M5 1959 (Box 38)
  - Day of the locust with an introduction by Richard B. Gehman. New York: New Directions, 1950, Call number: PS3545.E8334 D3 1950 (Box 58)
  - From ritual to romance Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1957, Call number: PN686.G7 W45 1957 (Box 38)
  - Age of innocence with a foreword by Louis Auchincloss. New York: New American Library, 1962, Call number: PS3545.H16 A35 1962b (Box 38)
  - House of mirth with an afterword by Louis Auchincloss. New York: The New American Library, 1964, Call number: PS3545.H16 H68 1964 (Box 38)
  - Hudson River bracketed with an afterword by Louis Auchincloss. New York: New American Library, 1962, Call number: PS3545.H16 H8 1962 (Box 38)
  - Three philosophical voyages Introduction and notes by Julian Eugene White, Jr. [New York: Dell Pub. Co.], 1964, Call number: PQ1793.A215 1964 (Box 32)
  - Obsession. Derby, Conn.: Monarch Books, 1963, Call number: PS3573.H4738 O27 1963 (Box 37)
  - Bestiary, a book of beasts: being a translation from a Latin bestiary of the twelfth century made and edited by T. H. White. New York: Putnam's, 1960, Call number: PA8275.B4 E5 1960 (Box 38)
  - Making of the President, 1960. New York: Pocket Books, 1961, Call number: E840.W5 1961 (Box 37)
  - Science and philosophy. New York: Philosophical Library, 1948, Call number: Q175.W62 1948 (Box 38)
  - Process and reality: an essay in cosmology; Gifford lectures delivered in the University of Edinburgh during the session 1927-28. New York: The Macmillan Company; Cambridge, Eng., University Press, 1929, Call number: BD511.W5 1929 (Box 59)
  - Leaves of grass with an introduction by Gay Wilson Allen. New York: New American Library, 1960, Call number: PS3201 1960 (Box 37)
  - Self-made man: and other poems. New York: Macmillan, 1959, Call number: PS3545.H868 S4 1959 (Box 39)
  - Devil must. New York: Popular Library, 1957, Call number: PS3573.I25 D48 1957 (Box 42)
  - Plough the sea. New York: Bantam Books, 1962, Call number: PS3545.I343 P5 1962 (Box 20)
  - Three plays: Our town, The skin of our teeth, The matchmaker illustrated by Alex Tsao; with a preface by the author. New York: Bantam Books, 1961, Call number: PS3545.I345 A19 1961 (Box 5)
  - Ides of March. New York: New American Library, 1963, Call number: PS3545.W65i 1963 (Box 20)